# **Vladimir Papchenko** Last update on March 6, 2020

v.e.papchenko@gmail.com • +972 53-543-9214 • www.linkedin.com/in/vladimir-papchenko • github.com/gecec Israel

### Summary

I am a software developer and dedicated to making cool things work. I know how to make processing of real-life data effective and stable, what algorithms to choose in each case for the best performance. I can design and implement useful and maintainable API and choose the best way to store and process data. I learned a number of programming languages on my programming journey started in 2000 including Pascal/Delphi, ABAP, Java, so I'm languageagnostic and ready to learn a new one in time of need, although Java remains my main language for the last several years.

#### Skills

Technical expertise: Software design and implementation, with(in) a team. Solid knowledge of algorithms, Object Oriented Programming, Java Core, design patterns, J2EE, Spring Framework (boot, core, web, security, jdbc templates), EJB, REST, Swagger, SQL, SOAP, JAX-RS, MyBatis, Liquibase, JUnit, Mockito, Tomcat, JBoss/Wildfly, Git, Maven, Hudson/Jenkins, Docker, Jira, GitLab, microservice architecture. Has experience with many data storage technologies: PostgreSQL, Oracle, MS SQL Server, MongoDB. Has base knowledge of frontend technologies: HTML, CSS, Javascript, JSF, Primefaces, Angular JS, React JS. Linux advanced user (Debian, Ubuntu, RHEL).

Natural languages: English (fluent), Hebrew (intermediate), Russian (native)

# Experience

Verint Systems **ISRAEL** 2019 - now

# **Software Developer**

Backend development using Java, Spring Framework, Wildfly, PostgreSQL, ElasticSearch, Docker.

Freelance

### **Software Developer**

2018 - 2019

I worked as a freelancer for a small project that helped to manage and monitor self-driving trucks. I was developing a backend and frontend parts of the system. Backend was built using Java, Spring Boot, Docker and MongoDB, frontend - using React[S and Leaflet[S. I also took part in system design and architecture development.

**RTLabs** Samara, Russia

## Java Developer

2017 - 2019

RTLabs is a big development company that builds large scalable systems for electronic government, also supplying many other services. I was developing projects helping to design protocols and interfaces for messaging through a huge information bus. Firstly, I rewrote one of the projects from Java 7 to Java 8 and Spring Framework (used DI, boot, Web, security). Then I was a leading backend developer at the next project, took part in building of system architecture, implemented backend (Java, PostgreSQL) and frontend parts (JSF). I also participated in several side projects in Java mostly making backend parts and small pieces of frontend (in AngularJS).

Gazprom Inform Samara, Russia

### **Lead Software Engineer**

2013 - 2017

Gazprom Inform is an IT-company providing solutions based on SAP for Gazprom branches. I was an ABAP developer and I was responsible for development of accounting, financial and real-estate modules of SAP project for a big Gazprom branch.

**RZD** Samara, Russia

#### Software Developer

2008 - 2012

I was working at a huge IT-department of Russian Railway company (RZD). I was a software developer in Java(Spring, Tomcat), Delphi, PHP, Javascript. I used Oracle and MS SQL Server databases. Also I was developing infrastructure tools in Perl, Python and Bash.

#### Education

### Samara State Railway University

Samara, Russia

### Master degree in Computer Science

2004 - 2009

Got knowledge of computer science, software design and development, information theory, cybersecurity and networks.